Yeah, great day. Uh attitude, uh
Seahawks, like through and through guys
like competitors,
uh athletes,
tough uh just great job by Josh and
Ryan, like really getting to know the
the uh the people, the competitors, and
and um
yeah, it was it was a it was a it was a
fun day. and and and we were able to
make a trade.
>> So, we give Pittsburgh a lot of credit
for doing a great job and working with
us. [snorts]
We had number of um
can't wait to give these guys credit. We
had a number of teams like, you know,
kind of go away on us. But, uh anyway,
yeah. No, it was it was it was a great
day.
>> John, we've heard you talk about wanting
to get draft picks who are going to come
in and come in with the mindset of
wanting to compete with guys and just
raise that level.
>> Absolutely. Yeah. from talking to these
guys for five minutes on a conference
call, they sound like they're going to
bring some of that.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. It's interesting. Uh Dave told us
that uh Julian was like that with you
guys, too. In in reputation wise, he's
just been a fairly quiet guy, but like
he's a really confident
um
athlete and you know, he's been through
a lot. uh the the young hipper scouts,
you know, they they have a saying for uh
leveling up and this guy's done it. You
know, he ch went to Fresno, enrolled at
Stanford for a minute and then, you
know, want to challenge himself in the
SEC and he did it. Performed at a high
level [snorts] and uh
yeah, no, they're they're both really
confident guys. Bud Bud's going to be
you guys are Bud's going to be fun, too.
He's he's a he's a blast. We were
talking, Mike and I were talking about
like the personalities like throughout
the process like man if we put Bud and
Spoon in the same room like what's going
to happen Nick in his second year you
know so
>> you prioritize how much [snorts] longing
do you have to do to find those
>> a deep dive if you may
>> Yeah deep dive yes yeah go back and do a
deep dive no uh
our guys just do a great job of getting
to know the people and we have a great
cohesion in our in our room. you know,
all the guys that go in over the top to
the schools too, you know, um Aaron and
and uh JB and Jason Barnes and, you
know, Matt Barry and Trent and all the
crosschecking that goes on and and then
all the in interviews we have with the
guys, you know, at the All-Star games
throughout the spring with the scouts
and then when the coaches come in, all
those Zoom meetings are just so
important. And um and then having the
guys in here as well. Bud came in on a
30 and everybody had a blast with him.
>> Julian told us that the combine
was gonna be I guess what if the com
stood out that
>> Well, I think um
I think there's a there's a clearly like
a competitor and a confidence in there.
Um takes a lot of pride in how physical
he is, you know, at the corner position.
and he's played safety as well. But um
yeah, Leslie looks like a pretty smart
guy. It's pretty cool. [laughter]
>> Right. But
>> turns out Leslie's pretty knows what
he's doing.
>> Regarding Bud, [clears throat] how
important was it to to replace Kobe and
say, "Oh, like let's have similar
attributes in that regard." Or did that
not steer your your thinking with him at
all?
>> Yeah. Uh I I don't I don't think we
think through like in those terms that
we're like we're we're not trying to
replace anybody. We're just trying to
find like the best people for us. And uh
and Bud has like a really great cool
like exciting skill set and personality
um competitive spirit to him. I mean
like the thing you know we're going to
we're not just going to play him at
safety. He can play nickel could
probably play corner for us. Um, we'll
figure that out kind of as we go and how
how the how the team kind of, you know,
shapes out. But, um, we got we got some
some really great players at safety,
too, that are going to compete. I mean,
Tai Cott won a lot of games, helped win
us a lot of games last year. Uh, Rodney
Thomas is is a guy that we're really
high on. um a lot of guys. So, you know,
it's a lot of going to be a lot of great
competition, but uh Bud has the skill
sets that we're looking for in our
secondary play with the competitiveness,
the ball skills, uh the man-to-man
ability, that that type of stuff.
>> You guys obviously didn't know at the
end of day one, um who you were going to
be able to get on day two. Now that you
have that behind you, like, uh how did
the draft fall relative to how you were
hoping it would fall through through two
days?
Yeah, Matt Perry sent me a text on
Friday morning with these three guys
names. It's like, okay. So, [laughter]
and we did we did like kind of like, you
know,
like just kind of scrimmage us out a lot
like you know through, okay, is it a
runner or a corner, a corner, a runner,
you know what I mean? All the way
through it like that. And um no, we're
just we're we're really excited. Um
yeah, just to be able to, you know, that
balance of, you know, best player, team
need really, really held true. So, um,
>> yeah, it was exciting.
>> Was that last Friday he text you that or
was that
>> Sorry, I apologize. [laughter] Thursday
morning, yesterday morning.
>> How important was it to add another
obviously
>> huge? Yeah, we almost added another one,
too. But we uh we decided to stay in and
and and pick. So
>> Oh, which pick was that?
>> Sorry.
>> Which was that? The third third round
pick the second round?
>> Oh, no. Well, I'm not going to tell you.
>> I mean, it's a great try, but
>> to add to your
project,
>> I'll tell you later.
>> A different program across the country.
What do you consider?
>> Uh
I mean I I know I don't actually I don't
know how much it's changed, you know. I
mean like I think I think uh
I think the way that we've been able to
like bring our coaching staff
like kind of in concert with the way
that we've done it here for a long time
and our personnel people and um it's not
like we came in and said this is what we
want. It was like we came together and
we both sides said like this is kind of
how we want to build it and that's
grown. I think it's evolved since we
since we got here and uh it's just like
that makes it a really fun process and
so it's easy to trust when when guys
like Brian Florence is saying that you
know he believes in a certain guy or um
our scouts and stuff. So like that it's
a really fun process you know that we
can get aligned and have um have buyin
kind of across all levels which is
really cool. So, what traits of these
two guys figure? How do they
>> Well, I think this is a great example of
that. It's like he asked yesterday about
about um JD like
his personality is way different than
Julian's, which is way different than
Buds, but they're all like we all
believe that they're see I mean Spoon's
different personality than Leo. I mean,
it's just but they have those core like
competitive fun. They got swag, they got
confidence, they but they have humility.
Uh, I mean they play an exciting brand
of football, you know, which we feel
like we're excited to work with. So, I
think that's the common denominator.
>> Mike Julian,
>> they understand it's the ultimate team
sport. They have that like self
awareness, self-sacrifice like like all
the lessons everybody's whoever in the
room has played football has learned
from the game.
>> Yeah.
>> Where do you see him at the NFL where
his
Yeah, we see him playing corner and I
think that's one of the exciting parts
about where he is is like there's so
much room for growth. He's already
playing a really good brand of football.
Um he has great traits. He's got a great
work ethic, super competitive. He's
smart. I mean those are all the
ingredients that um we believe can add
up to, you know, playing even better
football as his as his career grows. So
it's it's pretty cool.
>> When you guys talk about the attributes,
what's a Seahawk? You two won a Super
Bowl together. Does that in any way be
more convicted about this like double
down on this because it it worked. Is it
was there some stamp of certainty that
that winning the Super Bowl gives you
with regards to your your uh your
thoughts and plans on
>> I think this one you [laughter]
>> uh I not to like go all like wax poetic
but like whether or not we won
how the game like what the Super
happened in the Super Bowl last year. I
think we all felt that um
our process was like worth chasing and
and like and like and preserving
honestly, you know, and and uh like
we're really proud of the team that we
were able to build last year and how we
did it and the people on the team. And I
say team, I'm saying like everybody in
the building, all 70 guys, coaches,
staff. So, um, I think it's more of a
product of just kind of attacking the
like what we want to like the vision of
who we want to become over the course of
two years. I think we're more conf, you
know, I think it's having the results
for it definitely helps, but I don't
think it I don't think if we won the
game or lost the game, we would have we
would have changed anything.
>> Mike, you stops. It stops and it all
starts again. You know, it's like this,
okay, well, that's the last game. no
matter if you made the playoffs, didn't
make the playoffs, whatever. Now, okay,
here you go. Like, here's our next round
of the process.
>> Mike, you talk about how having the same
guys on the field that can get into
different structures is [snorts] an
important like evolution and these two
guys uh that you drafted today have
experience at different positions. How
much does that versatility play into how
you play defense?
>> Uh,
it's really important. It's really
important. I when I you got to be
careful when you say versatility because
to be like a jack of all trades master
and none is not really our brand of ball
like so we got to be uh intentional on
how we play our players but uh but as
we've seen like last year like we you
need guys to be able to do different
things uh whether it's through like
attrition you know over the course of
the season or
um you know as you build out your
systems on like the things you need to
be able to do obviously being able to do
more is better, you know, but it's our
responsibility as coaches to make sure
it's, you know, refined and focused
enough that it's still in like our guys'
wheelhouse so they can go, you know,
they can go play their best their best
ball and let their talent shine. So that
but that's why you go through the
process, you know, that's why you do fa
you attack phase one like crazy and you
know, you just respect those all those
importance of each day because that'll
that'll kind of bring everything into
focus.
>> Clark Clark had 15 interceptions at at
TCU. How just kind of his playmaking
ability?
>> Is that good? Poor. [laughter]
>> That's pretty good.
>> We'll give him credit when he's here,
but he probably should have had 30.
[snorts]
>> He he like, you know, he dropped he
dropped like he's got gets his hands on
a lot of balls. Let's put it that way.
>> Sound like he played really well at the
Senior Bowl, too. Um just kind of is his
take there to kind of stand out to you?
>> Um yeah, I thought the coolest part
about the Senior Bowl was like he just
took a ton of one-on-one snap or ton of
one-on-one reps, you know? I don't know
how they do it, but it seemed like he
was the guy in every other every other
rep and he was, you know, he was
covering people. And so that that was
for me that was that was really cool.
That was that was awesome.
>> He's really aggressive. Is there is
there how much of a balancing act is
there when you're deal quarterbacks, NFL
offenses with you want to play
aggressive, but you also This is the
NFL.
>> Yeah, it's a good point. It's it's a
balance, right? It's I mean we we want
to train them the way we we train our
our people and play within the system,
but you can't can't coach the player out
of the player. So, I think that's going
to come again, you got to go through the
process. You got to get a good feeling
for the things that you're seeing and
and uh you know and then like but that's
why you practice you know just you know
go make those decisive decisions in
practice and and then kind of go through
the process that way and and coach him
up and go you know just one play at a
time you know but the thing you can't
coach is his ability to go get it you
know so that you don't you don't want to
take that away from him. Obviously,
there was the attempts earlier to try
and move down, but staying where you
were for the most part and still getting
these guys, you know, Julian saying,
"We're gonna go back to back." Like
getting those kind of guys.
>> What did you say?
>> He said we're go back to back.
>> Julian say [laughter]
we'll talk to him about mass.
>> Maybe it was the wrong scouting report.
I [laughter]
>> He's a confident sucker.
>> Was there a question? you know, kind of
maybe didn't work out, but it still work
out. We get these guys that are Seahawks
that confident these kind of players.
How special is that?
>> Yeah, it's great. I mean, it's
like uh Brian Flurry would say, it's
very enjoyable enjoyable enjoyable tape
to watch.
>> Yeah, he has a funny thing. He's like,
"Yeah, I really enjoyed watching this
guy's tape. It's very enjoyable."
>> So, we're getting to learn Brian. It's
fun. I think I think it just speaks to
the pro like trust the process, you
know, like
>> and I think and not because he's sitting
here, but like just to see how John
operates the whole draft and with all
with the rest of our our staff and just
how well they work together and it's uh
it's really really cool to see it happen
in real time.
>> John, maybe Mike as well. How do you
balance that self-confidence and then
awareness [snorts] of the team? Where is
it in your home? Is that how has that
changed over the years when you hear
players? You have to be confident,
right?
>> Yeah. Yeah. Instead of Yeah. your
self-awareness. Yeah. I get it. Yeah.
No, we've learned a lot over the years,
you know. Um, and that's our that's our
our character process are are evaluating
the
the person and uh the connections that
everybody has to
that our scouts work their tails off to
reach out to, you know, have their
connections and spend the extra time to
figure out truly
is, you know, the competitor, the swag,
but yet having like a a
an awareness of not, you know, putting
yourself in front of the team.
>> John, how you going to handle tomorrow
morning?
>> Yeah, we said we had plenty of time to
to get ready for rookie free agency. We
could have had our meetings like
tomorrow. You know, I think that our
estimated our estimated time to pick at
188 is like 12:03 or something like
that.
>> So, it's going to be a freaking blast.
>> Sit there and watch all these names come
off. It's really fun. And then
>> on Julian's physical how he called
himself the most physical corner in this
draft. Can you just talk about that part
of his game?
>> Yeah, that's actually that's cool that
he said that. It's actually the number
one thing that stood out to me when uh
when I first like when when the guys
were presenting, we first started
studying. I was like this guy like he
brings it. It's important to him and he
wants Yeah. He wants he wants to be
physical. uh if you're into you know 6'2
corners that have length and
>> want to tackle
>> John is there any adjustment in any way
that you make going to a draft with Mike
as opposed to with Pete
>> any adjustments?
>> Well just kind of approach like you know
obviously there must be some difference
in their personality. I'm not trying to
>> No, it's not there's no difference
whatsoever. Is that a um
No, it's it's it's getting to know the
it's getting to know obviously the head
coach, but getting to know the the guys
going to be spending time, you know, the
position coaches, the guys will be
spending time and, you know, what kind
of buy in are they going to have and and
do they want to coach the player and and
u
yeah, I mean, I know the mistakes that
I've made personally in the past and
what that looks like and so we've we've
learned from those things and, you know,
we don't want to repeat it. I mean, so
but no, it's a it's it's it's not it
it's it's different with all the
assistant coaches, I would say, more
than because you're always going to have
those private conversations like, okay,
you good? You good? You know, so
>> except in pregame, Mike doesn't want to
talk to me during pregame. [laughter]
Pete want to talk.